[SOUND] So the next step of the mantra is Zoom and Filter.
[背景声音] Ben Schneiderman 准则的下一步是缩放和筛选
So let's look at zooming.
让我们来看一下缩放
What does zooming do?
缩放是做什么的呢
Zooming helps us focus on a portion of the plotted data.
缩放帮助我们只关注绘制数据的某一部分
It removes extraneous data that's outside of our zoomed in area.
它去掉那些放大区域以外的无关数据
So here's an example of a plot of data across the United States.
这是一个横跨美国的数据图的例子
And in this case, we've zoomed in on a portion of the West to the Midwest.
在这个例子中 我们放大了西部到中西部的部分
And then we've zoomed in again on a portion of Northern California.
然后我们放大了北加州的一部分
And by zooming in at each of these levels,
通过对这些不同层面的放大
we're removing a large portion of our dataset.
我们可以去掉我们数据组的很大部分
So we can focus on a smaller
从而关注数据组中更小的一部分
And by expanding that smaller portion of our dataset to the entire screen,
将数据组的这一小部分放大到整个屏幕
it allows us to use the resolution of the entire display to display more details.
这样我们就可以用显示器的全部分辨率来显示更多的细节
So at the highest level, we're just showing the state boundaries, but
在最高的层面 我们只能显示州界线
as we zoom in, we can start to show county boundaries.
而当我们放大时 我们可以开始显示郡界线
And then at the finer level, we have enough room to where we can
而在更精细的层面 我们有足够的空间来
add the names of counties, and other data about each of the counties.
加上郡的名字 以及每个郡的其他一些数据
And so by focusing on a small portion of our data,
所以当我们只关注数据的一个小部分时
we can ignore large amounts of data.
我们可以忽略大量的数据
And we can add more detail about the data we're specifically looking at,
然后我们可以给我们关注的数据增加很多细节
and so there's two ways of zooming.
缩放一共有两种方式
There's this way where we're looking at a portion of
一种是当我们要查看
the displayed coordinates of our datset by, for example, clicking a window.
数据组中可见坐标的一部分时 我们可以 例如 点击一个窗口
Or we can also expand axis fields.
另一种是扩大坐标轴的区域
So for example, if you're plotting data over time,
比如 如果你根据时间绘制数据
you might be looking at it by year.
你可以用年份查看它
If you want to focus on the year 2014 then you could click on 2014, and
如果你想关注2014年 你可以点击2014
expand that into quarters.
然后将它展开到季度
And we could look at, say, the first three quarters of 2014, and ignore 2013 and
我们可以查看 比如 2014的前三个季度 并忽略2013和
So we can use our resolution to more clearly see what's happening
我们可以用全部分辨率来更清楚地看到
at each quarter.
每个季度发生的事情
And then, we may be interested in Q2, and you could expand that.
然后 也许我们对第二季度感兴趣 你可以展开它
And look at the individual months, April, May and June of Q2, and ignore,
查看每个月 第二季度的四 五 六月
for example, the months in Q1 and Q3.
忽略 比如 第一和第三季度
So in each of these cases, zooming allows us to take the displayed data,
在这些例子中 缩放使我们能够将可见的数据
and to expand it to be able to focus on a portion of the displayed data.
展开 这样我们可以只专注于其中某一部分
And ignore the rest of our dataset that's not in that subset of our displayed data.
并忽略其余未被显示的数据子集
So here we've used Tableau to plot our life expectancy data versus population for
这里我们用Tableau绘制了世界上每个国家
every country in the world, and some of the data clumps up.
预期寿命和人口的对比图 有一些数据点堆叠在一起
We have a big collection here of a bunch of countries that have similar populations
在这里 有很多的国家
and life expectancy.
它们的人口和预期寿命都相似
And there's not enough resolution to be able to know which
而没有足够的分辨率来让我们知道
one we're pointing at if we're looking at that.
我们选取的是否是想要的数据点
So if I want to find out in these clumpy areas what's going on,
所以当我想了解这些密集区域的内容
I would zoom, and so it would show the Zoom Controls.
我会选择缩放 它会显示缩放控制键
Go over here and zoom in on this data, and that will spread things out.
这里 然后放大数据 这样数据点就会散开
And I can see, for example, this clump was Norway, Singapore,
我可以看到 比如 这一块区域里面有挪威 新加坡
and New Zealand that all have similar populations and life expectancies.
以及新西兰 它们都有相似的人口和预期寿命
And some of these other clumps can be differentiated.
另一些密集区也可以被区分开来
For example, West Bank, and Gaza, and Lithuania
比如 约旦河西岸 加沙以及立陶宛
have similar life expectancy in populations, or
有相似的预期寿命和人口
over here we've got Argentina and Poland.
这边我们有阿根廷和波兰
And so by zooming in on the data, we can use the resolution available on our
这样通过放大数据 我们可以用显示屏的
Display Screen to better differentiate similar items.
分辨率来更好地区分类似的数据项
And then we can always zoom back if we want to see where things are in
我们如果想要找到数据点在全局中的位置
the original context.
也可以缩小回去
When we zoom in on a portion of our plotted data we're ignoring, we're
当我们放大一块绘图上的数据时
completely ignoring, the portion of the data that's outside of that zoom window.
会完全忽略在放大的窗口以外的数据
Often that can cause us to get lost in the data.
通常这会使我们迷失在数据中
We're looking at a fine level, and we forget where that fine level of data that
当我们在查看精细的层面时 会忘记所关注的精细层面的数据
we're focusing on sits within the larger dataset.
在整个大数据组中的方位
So, there are tools that help us to combine the focus of zooming with
于是 有一些工具 帮助我们结合缩放时的焦点和
the context of the big picture of the entire dataset.
整个数据组的背景
And, these are called lenses.
它们被称为透镜
They're interactive lenses that you can drag around.
它们是可互动的透镜 你可以随意拖动它们
Sometimes they're called magic lenses, depending on what they show.
根据所显示的内容 有时候它们也被称为魔术透镜
And they allow you to zoom in on details.
它们可以让你放大细节
For example, here's a dataset, and we can drag around this zoom lens.
例如 在这个数据组上 我们可以拖动这个透镜
And it uniformly magnifies everything underneath it, but
它会以同一程度放大在它下面的内容 但
you can still see where you are relative to the large dataset.
你还是可以看到你在大数据组的位置
But in this case, we have a uniform level of magnification,
不过这个例子中 放大率是固定的
so the data that's underneath the periphery of this lens is being obscured.
这样在这个透镜下但处在边缘的数据就被遮挡了
We're magnifying this portion of the data but for example,
例如 我们在放大数据的这个部分时
we've really lost the detail of the region of data away from that magnified edge.
就失去了被放大数据之外区域的细节
Because it's being obscured by the magnified data.
因为它们被那些放大了的数据挡住了
There are fisheye distortion lenses that help fix that problem.
鱼眼变形透镜可以帮助解决这个问题
In a fisheye lens, you've got a lot of magnification at the center of the lens.
在鱼眼透镜中 透镜中心部位会放大很多
And as you move away from the center, you've got less magnification.
而离中心越远 放大越小
And as you get towards the periphery of the lens, you get no magnification.
当到达透镜边缘 就完全没有放大效果了
The magnification goes to one, and so you basically as you cross the lens,
即放大倍率为1 于是在透镜的边缘
you don't see any change in magnification.
你不会看到放大效果
That way we can push away some of the details from the center, and
这样我们可以从中心的细节处移开 然后
we get this seamless transition from the outer context
我们得到从外部内容到内部细节放大
into the zoom details that we're looking at.
的无缝过渡
In this case, these three spheres, these three light green spheres,
比如 这三个浅绿色的球体
are the three large spheres that were basically occluding everything here.
它们太大了以至于把这里所有东西都挡住
And as we push them away, because they're away from the center,
而当我们将它们移开时 由于它们不再处于中心位置
we can start to magnify five very,
我们可以放大这五个
very small spheres that were being occluded by these large spheres.
之前被挡住的非常小的球体
For example, these three spheres are basically these three spheres.
比如 这三个球体
They're uniformly distributed one, two, three here, and
它们均匀地分布着 一 二  三
you can see that the first sphere here is farther away than the other two.
你可以看到第一个球体比其他两个离得更远
That's because of the magnification of this sphere is greater than
这是因为在这个球体上的放大率
the magnification of these spheres.
比其他球体高
And so the distance is getting magnified more here than it was here.
所以比起原来 这里的距离也被放大了
And so these fisheye distortion lenses give us a nice combination
这种鱼眼变形透镜使我们既可以
of the ability to zoom in on data, but to see it in a context of the big picture.
放大数据也可以看到放大的数据在整个图中的位置
So the D3 JavaScript library has some good tools for
D3 JavaScript库里有一些优秀的鱼眼变形
doing a fisheye distortion that nicely demonstrated.
的工具以及范例
So here, for example, we have a graph, and
举个例子 在这个图上
you can see that the graph contains a lot of clusters of nodes.
你可以看到很多堆叠在一起的节点
And it's hard to see what's going on with all the edges inside those clusters.
要看清楚这些堆叠节点的边界非常困难
But if I put the mouse near it, than we get a magnification, and
但当我把鼠标移过去 它们就被放大了 然后
you can start to see the differences.
你就可以分辨彼此
There's still a lot of lines there, but you can magnify the positions
此外还有很多线条 但你可以用鱼眼变形透镜
of the nodes, spread the nodes out with this fisheye distortion lens.
放大这些位置 将节点分散开来
And see what's going on with the edges,
看清楚它们之间的界线时
while still connecting to the context of the remainder of the graph.
同时还可以看到它与图表其余部分的联系
So you still get your big picture of the whole graph.
你既能看得到整个图的宏观情况
You can zoom in on individual elements.
又可以放大单个元素
And later on in the page, they show an example of how this distortion works.
在本页的后面 它们举例子来说明变形的原理
It's basically creating a small vector field that offsets the vertices or
基本上 它创造一个小矢量场 它会根据你看的是原始数据或左顶点
pixels, depending on if you're looking at primitive data, left vertices, or
还是有像素的图形数据
if you're looking at image data with pixels.
来补偿顶点或像素
And then you can do
然后你可以
the lensing to the entire screen in a rectal-linear way, or
线性地放大整个屏幕
you can just do it to a small cylindrical or a small disk-shaped portion.
或者放大柱形或圆盘形的一小部分
And here's some other data.
这是另外一些数据
In this case, you've got data that's plotted by area, and
这里数据是根据面积来绘制的 所以
there's a lot of overlap, and a lot of small details and large details.
有很多的重叠部分 有很多小的和大的细节
And as you drag over these regions, by distorting the entire field, then
当你拖拽过这些区域 通过让整个图形变形
you can see the intricate relationship between the data in your focus.
你就能看到焦点下数据之间的复杂关系
While still maintaining the context of where that data lies
同时看到这些数据
in the context of the rest of the dataset.
与数据组其余部分的位置关系
So these fisheye lenses provide a nice compromise of both focus and context.
就这样鱼眼透镜很好地平衡了聚焦与全局
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community